Alexinder Virdee

Miami, FL | (954) 616-9029 | alex@virdee.com

alexvirdee.com | LinkedIn.com/in/alexvirdee | github.com/alexvirdee

Profile

I am a Miami based web developer who loves technology and software development. I obtained my bachelor's degree at the University of Central Florida. I am a passionate problem solver always looking to learn new technologies in software development in order to utilize them and develop exciting applications. I currently have two years of experience working as a web developer in the healthcare industry with a focus on front-end technologies. I am excited, and look forward to a new opportunity that will contribute to the continuous development of my programming skills.

Technical Skills

JavaScript, Angular, Express.js, MongoDB, SQL, Node.js, SPARQL, RDF, Ember, React, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Grunt, AJAX, ¡Query, Responsive Design, Tailwinds, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub, Wordpress, Typescript.

Professional Experience

Web Application Developer

April 2018 - January 2020

INFOTECHSoft, Inc.

Miami. FL

- Web Developer tasked to the GeneTegra Platform Data Lakes and Baptist Health Projects committed to advancing biomedical research
- Utilized semantic web technologies such as SPARQL, RDF, and OWL to aggregate and query vast amounts of biomedical data
- Prepared and developed UX/UI mockup proposals using Balsamig wireframing software
- Tasked with developing and enhancing features for company applications making use of the JavaScript web framework Ember.js
- Worked through complex problem solving and fixed issues assigned through Jira
- Kept legacy application up to date implementing latest versions and testing code with QUnit
- Used user input to develop, iterate, and ship applications in a swift efficient manner
- Skilled in the software development life cycle, improving overall quality of applications by using Jira project management software & Kanban methodology

Teaching Assistant

May 2018 - August 2018

University of Miami

Miami. FL

- Part time worked with students to program the basic fundamentals of JavaScript
- Developed trust and rapport with class to code final project applications starting with design and building REST APIs with NodeJS & front-end interfaces with React
- The course successfully covered the MERN stack || MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS

Education

Ironhack

January 2018 - March 2018

- Miami, FL
 - Ironhack is an immersive web development bootcamp with locations in Madrid, Barcelona, and Miami. The program has a fast paced setting with a highly selective cohort of students. (400+
 - Technologies learned: JavaScript, Angular 2, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, HTML, CSS, Sass, ¡Query, Bootstrap, Git

University of Central Florida

August 2012 - August 2016

Orlando. FL

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration - Management, Entrepreneurial Track